Finding Aid for the Allen Sapp Score Collection, circa 1936-1992
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Arrangements, Transcriptions, and Analyses of Other Composer’s Works, circa 1939-1950, VII.; Box 31 (folder 1-6)
  - Arrangements of piano works for strings. 3 pencil and ink manuscripts, most works short excerpts, type="inclusive">undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    Sonata op. 53; Traumerei, R. Schumann; Sonatina in C Major, Clementi; Serenade, Prelude, Melody, Moment Musicale, March, Fur Elise, Anitra’s Dance, Hungarian Dance, To the Moon, Salut D’amor, La Cinquantine, Funeral March
  - Transcriptions. Multilith masters., type="inclusive">undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
    Nuper Rosarum, Dufay; Missa L’Homme Arme, Palestrina; Messe Notre Dame, Machaut
  - Analysis. Ink manuscript, 83 p., type="inclusive">undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
    Quintet Op. 26, Schoenberg
    Title page text: "An analysis according to an original method of the Quintet Op. 26 of Arnold Schoenberg. All the notes of the original Quintet are shown but their function, from a twelve-tone standpoint, is represented by color which denotes the basic form of the tone row and by letter which denotes the position of each note in the statement of the row."
  - Analysis. 2p., type="inclusive">undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
    Klavierstück Op. 33a, Schoenberg
    Different colors also used for tone-row forms.
  - Arrangement. Pencil manuscript, 6 p., type="inclusive">undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
    Atto Secondo (Selection from Act II of Orfeo, Monteverdi)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Music--Scores and parts; Sapp, Allen, 1922-1999--Manuscripts
Genres
Scores
Associated Material
Additional Guides
All scores in the collection are cataloged in OCLC and are available in WorldCat and BISON, the online catalog for the University at Buffalo Libraries, by performing a "Title begins with" search under "Allen Sapp Score Collection".
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Allen Sapp Papers
Mus. Arc. 11.2
Largely unprocessed collection of documents and correspondence documenting the life of Allen Sapp.